DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
多米尼加共和国
All right, we're good to go.
准备好了
- You got this? - You bet your ass, bubba.
- 好了吗？ - 没问题
Let's make some money!
大赚一笔吧！
Everyone in position.
各就各位！
l thought we'd be robbing banks by now,
我还以为我们要抢银行
not some gas truck in the middle of nowhere.
而不是在这前不着村后不着店 的地方抢油罐车
Down here, gas is gold, bubba.
在这 石油就是黄金
Yeah, But banks don't move.
是啊 可是银行不会乱跑
Anytime you get near a bank...we have to break your ass out of prison.
每次你靠近银行 我们都要把你从牢里弄出来
Kill the chatter! Game time.
别聊了 开始干活
l wouldn't piss him off, guys.
我可不想惹恼他 伙计们
Yeah, yeah, I hear you.
听到啦
Hey, you greedy bitch!
贪吃的家伙
Okay, guys, we're gonna have to hit this hard and fast.
我们要麻利点
We got four K left before the downgrade.
还有4公里就下坡了
Locked and loaded!
接好了！
This is all you, Han.
都是你的 韩
Liquid gold.
液体黄金
We're clear.
我们搞定了
Okay, T, you're up.
提戈 该你们了
Let's see if you can get it under six tries this time, huh, T?
看看你6次以内能否搞定
What are you talking about? I'll do it in one try!
说什么呢 这回一次搞定
Lt's more like three. Come on, Tego, keep it real.
三次差不多 好啦 提戈 动真格的了
Just one K left. We're running out of road. Get in there, brother.
还剩1公里 前面没路了 动作快点 老弟
I got it, I got it.
明白
Shit!
糟糕！
T, cut loose! Unhitch, unhitch!
提戈 快松开！
- Don't be crazy.lose your load! - What do you think I'm trying to do?
- 别犯傻 松开挂钩！ - 你以为我在干什么！
...idiot,just release!
笨蛋 快松开！
- Spray that hitch! - I don't have a hammer!
- 喷那个挂钩！ - 我没有锤子！
Just do it!
做吧！
Hold on! Hold on!
抓紧！抓紧！
No shit!
不！
Hold onto something tight!
抓紧点！
Letty!
莱蒂！
- Give me your hand! - I can't reach!
- 抓住我的手！ - 我够不到！
You got to jump!
跳！
Jump!
Letty, jump!
莱蒂 跳！
I've got you!
我接着你！
Dom...
多姆…
Dom?
多姆？
Dom!
多姆！
《速度与激情4》
Mi primo is running security on the airbase.
普莱莫在机场当保安
Says that there's going to be a couple of refueling planes arriving.
他说要来几架运油机
HAN: How you doing?
你好吗？
OMAR: Money, money!
钱！钱！
Good.
不错
OMAR: Yo, why your stack is bigger than mine always?
为什么你那一叠总比我的厚？
I'm supersized, baby.
我是大号的 伙计
Go have fun.
找点乐子去
Cops just raided our garage in Baracoa.
警察突击了我们在巴拉科阿的修车厂
They were real interested in you.
他们要抓的是你
Heat's on and we just sent up a flare that's gonna lead them right to us.
我们刚刚又给他们留下了线索
l say we move out first thing in the morning.
我们明早就离开这
Nah, it's me they want.
不 他们要抓的是我
And if they catch me,
如果他们抓住我
they're throwing big numbers at anybody with me.
他们会把与我有牵连的人都投入大牢
Han, we had a good run.
韩 我们做得不错
Time for you to go do your own thing.
你该去做些自己的事情了
Heard they're doing some crazy shit in Tokyo.
听说他们在东京很疯狂
Have you seen Letty?
见到莱蒂了吗？
There she is.
她在那
I hear Rio is nice this time of year.
我听说里约每年这时候很美
The cops are getting hungrier.
警察追得越来越紧
Then I guess we're doing our job.
这就是我们的生活
I'm a walking target.
我是个移动的目标
I don't want you around when they catch up to me.
我不想被抓住的时候让你受牵连
"Ride or die," remember?
“不开车就去死” 还记得吗？
Dom, how long have we been doing this?
多姆 我们干这行多久了？
And now all of a sudden, out of nowhere, it's too dangerous?
突然之间 凭空就说这很危险了？
Come on.
好啦
We'll figure it out. We always do.
我们能化险为夷的 一向如此
DOWNTOWN LOS ANGELES
洛杉矶市区
- I don't know shit! - Give me a name!
- 我什么都不知道！ - 告诉我他的名字！
- I don't know shit, man! - Give me a name!
David Park! David Park's the guy you want!
大卫·帕克！他就是你要找的人！
Please!
别开枪！
Thank God. Listen, he's in a mood because yesterday was his cheat day,
感谢上帝 听着 他没发火因为昨天他偷懒没锻炼
and then today, some genius brought in donuts.
今天 有人拿来了甜甜圈
Great.
很好
Sorry I'm late.
对不起来晚了
Complaints keep rolling in after your little downtown Olympics, O'Conner.
你在市区闹运之后就投诉不断
Tell me that reinstating you wasn't a mistake.
告诉我给你复职不是错误
- I got a name. David Park. - That's it?
- 我拿到个名字 大卫·帕克 - 就这个？
That's all you got? David Park?
就听到个大卫·帕克？
I could throw a fortune cookie out this window and hit 50 David Parks right now.
从这窗户扔出去块点心 能砸到50个大卫·帕克
- It's Korean, not Chinese. - Whatever.
- 是韩国人 不是中国人 - 随便
Park is a scout that recruits street racers to be mules for the Braga cartel.
帕克召集街头车手给布拉加运货
We find Park, and we bust the bad guys.
我们找到帕克 就能将他们一网打尽
PANAMA CITY,PANAMA
巴拿马 巴拿马城
Dom.
多姆
Mia, I told you not to call me here.
米娅 我说过不要打到这里来
Dom, it's Letty.
多姆 是莱蒂
She's been murdered.
遇害了
We have gathered here to pay our final respects to...
我们到这里作最后致意…
Let us reflect on her journey...
我们来追忆她的旅程…
"The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want. He makes me lie down..."
“上帝是我的牧师 我本不需要 他使我接受…”
Facial recognition software matched Toretto
面部识别程序在特伦托
about 10 minutes after he crossed the border.
入境10分钟后发现了他
I don't get it.
我不明白
I thought he'd show.
我以为他会来的
I told you not to come. They're staking the place out.
我告诉你不要来的 他们在监视这里
- If they find you... - They won't.
- 如果他们发现你… - 不会的
Come on. Look at you.
好啦 瞧瞧你
Letty wouldn't let them junk it.
莱蒂不让他们处理掉它
Even though it is a goddamn curse.
即便它是个诅咒
When she came back, she was always in here,
她回来以后 就到这里
working on it day and night.
夜以继日地改进它
It was weird.
真是不可思议
It was like she knew you were coming back.
就好像她知道你会回来
I want to see the crash site.
我要看看出事现场
I just got off the phone with Deputy Director Lawson.
我刚和副局长通过电话
If we don't make serious inroads into the Braga case in the next 72 hours,
如果我们72小时内在布拉加的案子上还没进展
they're gonna shut us down.
我们就都下岗了
I know I'm a newbie here, but why the clock now?
我知道是新来的 但是为什么那么急？
Because it's been two years,
因为已经两年了
and the last three agents we sent to infiltrate his organization
我们派去卧底的三个探员
came back in body bags.
都裹着尸袋回来的
He's moved more heroin across the border than Escobar did in 10 years.
他运入境的海洛因比埃斯科巴10年的都多
This guy is becoming one of our biggest national threats,
这家伙成为国家安全最大的威胁之一
and we don't even have a picture of him.
我们连他的照片都没有
We don't have prints! Not even a goddamn DOB!
没有指纹！连出生日期都不知道！
What's the status on David Park?
大卫·帕克是什么人？
lsn't he our ticket into the Braga organization?
他是我们潜入布拉加组织的通行证？
We're running the name through city and county databases, sorting the possibilities.
我们通过数据库搜索 按可能性排序
We've got over 500 already.
已经有500个了
Park's insignificant. Sounds like another jerk-off to me.
帕克不重要 对我来说就是个小混混
It's not. Without Park, Braga wouldn't have drivers to move his shipments.
不是的 没有帕克介绍 布拉加不会让车手给他送货
Cross-check traffic. lllegal modifications.
监视交通 非法改装
Street racing. This guy will definitely have a record. We'll find him.
街头赛车 这家伙肯定有记录 我们会抓住他
We better.
最好如此
What do you know?
知道吗？
Your boy Toretto's red Chevelle has been spotted in his old neighborhood.
你那小子特伦托的红色雪佛兰 在他家附近出现
I'm going to bring his ass in.
我要把他抓来
Not in your car you're not.
你抓不到的
It's straight ahead.
就在前面
You found something back there.
你在那发现了什么
There were burn marks on the ground.
地面上有烧焦的痕迹
The kind that could only be caused by nitrometh.
只可能是硝基甲烷造成的
There's only one guy in all of L.A. that sells that.
洛杉矶只有一家卖这个
Nothing you can do is gonna bring her back, Dom.
无论怎样她都不会复生 多姆
If I were Letty, I would ask you...
如果我是莱蒂 我会要你…
No, I would beg you, please, let this go.
不 我求你 忘掉它吧
Before it's too late.
否则就太迟了
It's already too late.
已经太迟了
I love you.
我爱你
Miss Toretto.
特伦托小姐
I'm Michael Stasiak, FBI.
我叫迈克尔·斯特萨克 联邦调查局的
Let's you and I have a little chat.
我们需要谈谈
Hi. This is Forsythe in Evidence.
我是证据组的福赛斯
I need Stasiak down here right away to sign some greenies.
我要斯特萨克来登记证人
Thanks.
谢谢
Hi. Hey.
嘿
Okay, I narrowed it down to 50 or so David Parks.
我把范围缩小到50个大卫·帕克
What I'd like you to do is run the make and model on each one of them.
你要做的是查清他们每个的底细
- All right? - Okay. All right.
- 明白？ - 好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, Tyler, we got a transfer.
嘿 泰勒 我们换班了
You want to come with me?
和我来
Toretto.
特伦托
When'd you get back in town?
你什么时候回来的？
I'm looking for a car you did an engine mod on.
我在找一辆你改造过引擎的车
Nitromethane tank. Ford full-size. Continental tires.
硝基甲烷油箱 福特全尺寸 大陆牌轮胎
Look, what are you doing, coming in here like this, huh?
听着 你在干什么？ 就这样大摇大摆地进来？
This ain't your scene anymore, boss.
这不再是你的地盘了 老大
Don't ever put your hands on me again, okay?
别再来找我
Say hi to your sister for me.
代我向你妹妹问好
A Korean kid brought it in. David Park.
一个韩国小子 大卫·帕克
It's a green Ford Torino.
绿色福特都灵车
Please don't drop this on me!
别砸我！
I'm almost done.
我吃完了
Why don't you tell me why you dragged me here, Brian?
何不告诉我你为何带我到这来
You know they're going to capture Dom. Maybe worse.
你知道他们要抓多姆 也许更糟
I don't want you getting tangled up in this. So stay away from him.
我不想你卷入这件事 所以离他远点
That's what you have to say to me after five years?
5年了 这就是你要对我说的？
All of a sudden, you care what happens to me.
突然间 你就关心起我了
What I did to you was wrong.
我原来对不起你
I'm sorry. It was... It was the hardest thing I've ever had to do.
我很遗憾 那是… 我所做的最困难的事情
I'm sorry, too, Brian.
我也很遗憾 布莱恩
I'm so sorry that you had to come into my home and pretend to love me.
我很遗憾你闯进我家 假装爱我
I'm so sorry that you ripped my family apart.
我很遗憾你把我家搞得四分五裂
I'm very sorry that that was hard for you.
我非常遗憾这对你很难
I lied to you.
我对你撒了谎
I lied to Dom. I lied to everybody.
我对多姆撒了谎 对所有人撒了谎
That's what I do best. It's why the Feds recruited me.
这是我拿手的 因此联邦调查局招我进去
Maybe you're lying to yourself.
也许你在对自己撒谎
Maybe you're not the good guy pretending to be a bad guy.
也许你不是装作坏人的好人
Maybe you're the bad guy pretending to be the good guy.
也许你是装作好人的坏人
You ever think about that?
你想过吗
Every day.
每天都想
I always wondered,
我总在想
why did you let my brother go that day?
那天你为什么让我哥哥走？
I don't know.
我不知道
Shit.
唉
Brian!
布莱恩！
I got the cross-checks on David Park back and have a list of possibles.
我核查了大卫·帕克 列出了可能的名单
- What do you got? - All right. A 45-year-old male in a '06 Scion
- 上面有谁？ - 45岁男性 开06款Scion
- with three reckless driving tickets. - No.
- 有三张罚单 - 不是他
- An '01 Chevy Tahoe. - No.
- 01款雪佛兰塔荷 - 不是
Two Mini Coopers, a '06 and a '07, a Toyota hybrid.
两辆Mini Cooper 06和07款 丰田混合车
- Hell no. - A '98 Saturn, a '95 Sebring.
- 不是 - 98款Saturn 95款Sebring
A '98 Nissan 240 with an illegal mod.
98款尼桑240 非法改装过
Wait. That's it.
等等 就是它
- What? - The 240 with the illegal mod.
- 哪个？ - 非法改装的尼桑240
- How do you know? - 'Cause that's something I'd drive.
- 你怎么知道 - 因为是我会开的
Don't! Don't! Don't!
不要！
Green Torino, running nitro.
绿色都灵车 烧硝基甲烷
- Whose car? - I don't know, man.
- 谁的车？ - 我不知道
I'm just the middleman. I swear! I'm just the middleman!
我只是中间人 我发誓！ 我只是中间人
Wait, wait, wait.
等等
I don't know shit, man. I swear. I just run cars for Braga, all right?
我不知道 我发誓 我只是给布拉加开车的
All I can do is get you in the race! That's all I can do!
我能做的只有让你去参赛！ 就这些！
What race?
什么比赛？
Help! Come on, hold on!
救命！抓住啊！
Let me up, man! Come on!
把我拉上去 快！
Come on, man, I don't know shit! Just let me up!
快点啊！我什么都不知道！拉我上去！
I told you, you got to talk to Braga!
我说了 你要和布拉加去谈！
Bring him up, Dom.
把他拉上来 多姆
God! Don't drop me! That's all I know!
天啊！别放下我！我只知道这些！
Bring him up.
把他拉上来
You here to take me in, O'Conner?
你来抓我的 奥康纳？
- Shit! Shit! - Shut up!
- 靠！ - 闭嘴！
Letty was my friend, too.
莱蒂也是我的朋友
You weren't anyone's friend.
你没有朋友
Yo, can you guys talk about this later? Now pull my ass up!
你们能不能以后再谈这个？ 快把我拉上去！
She was running for this guy, Braga, and things went bad.
她在为这个布拉加做事 后来出了情况
Please!
求求你！
I'm going to get these guys, Dom.
我要抓住这帮人 多姆
Now let me do my job and bring him up.
让我来做我的工作 把他拉上来
I'm going to kill this Braga.
我要杀了布拉加
God!
天啊！
And anyone else who gets in my way.
还有挡我道的人
Hey!
嘿！
Don't let go.
别放手！
O'Conner!
奥康纳！
O'Conner! If you ever release a witness of mine again...
奥康纳！如果你再放走我的证人…
- That's enough! - Don't touch me.
- 够了！ - 别碰我
- I'm fine! - That's enough.
- 我没事 - 够了
- You're through, O'Conner! - I said that's enough!
- 你完了 奥康纳！ - 够了！
Stasiak, go get yourself cleaned up.
斯特萨克 去洗洗
What? He hit me first! You...
什么？他先打我的 你…
This isn't the Cub Scouts!
这不是童子军！
Now, go on! You're bleeding on my floor.
快去！血滴到我的地板了
O'Conner, do you know the difference between a cop and a criminal?
奥康纳？你知道警察和罪犯的区别吗？
- What? - One bad judgment call.
- 什么？ - 主观上的判断
Keep your shit in line, son.
规矩点 孩子
Have a good time.
祝你好运
Take a seat.
坐下
Good news. We have intel that Braga's number two, Ramon Campos,
好消息 内线说布拉加的二把手 雷蒙·坎波斯
will hold a street race in Koreatown tomorrow night
明晚要在韩国城举行街头车赛
to fill a slot on his team.
为他的队伍选拔人才
They've already chosen three drivers from previous races.
他们从前面的比赛中已经选中三个
Our newest informant, Mr. David Park,
我们最新的线人 大卫·帕克
has been kind enough to get us into the race.
让我们能够进入比赛
O'Conner, you're up.
奥康纳 该你了
Let me guess, winner gets the slot.
我猜是赢家获得位子
All right, so these are all the imports the city has in impound.
这就是本市扣押的车辆
- Okay, nice. - Pick your poison.
- 不错 - 挑一辆吧
All right, 2206. I crashed one of those.
2226号 我曾撞毁过一辆
3418 and 2765.
3418和2765号
Okay, so which one do you want?
你选哪辆？
I want them all.
都要了
Standard issue tracking device.
标准跟踪系统
Boss wants to know where you are at all times.
头要一直知道你在哪
You want to play with it?
你想玩玩吗？
Hey!
嘿！
What are you looking at, nutsack?
你在看什么 脓包？
I don't know. You tell me.
不知道 你说呢
The racer wants what Dwight's got.
车手想要德怀特的东西
See, but, ladies, Dwight's already on the team.
但是姑娘们 德怀特已经入选了
You got to be fast if you want to drive for Braga.
你要想给布拉加开车的话得快点
- Is there a problem here? - No.
- 有问题吗？ - 没
You one of Park's guys, blondie?
你是帕克找来的吧？
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
是的
Follow me.
跟我来
See you later, punk.
回头见 小子
You, too, punk.
你也是 小子
BulI's-eye, come on!
一击命中！
We can do this all day.
总能做到
You all know why you're here.
你们都知道为什么到这来
Good drivers
好的车手
are a dime a dozen.
实在太多了
Man, every corner's got a chingadera tuner racing for pinks.
靠开车泡妞的人太多了
That's not what Braga has got me looking for.
那不是布拉加让我找的
Braga wants someone that would sell their abuelita to be behind the wheel.
布拉加要的是能把一切抛在脑后的人
Someone that drives their 10-second cars not in a straight line,
不是规规矩矩地开跑车
but to push it and make it through places no one else would take it.
而是穿过没人能去的地方
Real drivers.
真正的车手
So, what are we hauling?
我们运什么？
For the money Braga's paying, you don't need to know.
布拉加付钱 你没必要知道
You just said you wanted real drivers.
你说你要真正的车手
A real driver knows exactly what's in his car.
真正的车手知道自己车里有什么
Mira, real driver,
真正的车手
nobody's forcing you to race.
没人逼你去开车
You the boss?
你是老大？
Or am I talking to the boss?
还是我和老大说话？
Do I look like a boss?
我看着像老大吗？
My job is to find the best drivers, period.
我的工作是找到最好的车手
Whoever wins the race gets the info. We cool?
谁赢得比赛谁就能知道 好不好？
Are we cool?
好不好？
Yeah, we're cool.
好吧
No, we ain't cool, man.
不太好
Who's closing these streets?
谁封闭街道？
No one. That's the point.
没人 这是关键
PIease wait whiIe directions are downIoaded.
导路下载中 请等待
Proceed to the highlighted route.
到加亮路线
Ten,
十
nine,
九
eight,
八
seven,
七
six...
六…
- You sure you want to do this? - A lot has changed.
- 你确定这么做？ - 很多事情变了
...four... You're right.
四… 说得没错
...three,
…三
two,
二
one,
一
go!
出发！
Right turn ahead.
前方右转
You are now five miIes from your destination.
距离目标5英里
How's my ass look, Chia Pet?
我的屁股怎么样 小子？
Ghetto Smurf.
犹太杂种
Dead man driving.
去死吧
Come on!
快啊！
Right turn ahead.
前方右转
Shit!
靠！
Damn.
见鬼
Rerouting.
重新计算路线
Proceed straight ahead.
前方直行
Rerouting.
重新计算路线
Shit.
靠
- Rerouting. - Just shut up!
- 重新计算路线 - 闭嘴！
You are 2.6 miIes from destination.
距离目标2.6英里
Oops, I didn't see you.
啊…没看到
You are now four and one-haIf miIes from your destination.
距离目标4.5英里
- U-turn, if possible. - Are you kidding me?
- U型转弯 可能的话 - 开玩笑吧？
You are now 4.2 miIes from your destination.
距离目标4.2英里
Sorry, car.
对不住了 爱车
You are now one miIe from your destination.
距离目标1英里
Yeah, guess who's back, Dom?
猜猜谁回来了 多姆？
Let's go!
加速！
Nice car, baby!
车不错 宝贝！
Bitch!
贱人！
You are now one-quarter mile from your destination.
距离目标四分之一英里
Too early, Dom.
太早啦 多姆
No!
不！
Still a buster.
还是个菜鸟
You have reached your destination. Goodbye.
到达目的地 再见
At least we know you can't beat me straight up.
至少你不耍赖赢不了我
I didn't know there were any rules.
我不知道规则一说
Now that's what I call real driving.
这就是我说的真正的车手
No, that's bullshit, man!
胡说八道！
Go cry to your mama, eh?
向你妈妈哭去吧
You work for Braga now.
你现在为布拉加工作了
When the GPS calls, you follow.
GPS呼叫时 你就跟着走
Driver's license.
驾驶执照
What driver's license?
什么驾驶执照？
Thumb.
大拇指
Cell phone number.
手机号码
The print is for Campos.
指纹是给坎波斯的
The number is for me.
号码是给我的
Yo, nutsack!
脓包！
Let me tell you something, man, muscle beats import every time.
告诉你吧 那个肌肉男总能打败新来的
You know what I'm saying? Every time!
你听清了？总能打败！
Ladies, let's get on back to Papa Dwight's.
姑娘们 回到德怀特叔叔这来吧
Papa Dwight wants you to take off your shoes.
德怀特叔叔要你们脱鞋
Dwight likes feet. Take off your shoes.
德怀特喜欢美脚 脱鞋吧
So beautiful.
真美
Dwight likes this foot a lot.
德怀特太喜欢了
Yes, baby!
宝贝！
- Daddy Dwight loves... - FBI!
- 德怀特喜欢… - 联邦调查局的
I didn't do nothing, man! Dwight didn't do nothing!
我什么都没做 德怀特什么都没做！
- Hey, no! Stay, stay! Where you going? - Bye, Dwight!
- 别走！你们去哪？ - 再见了 德怀特！
No, what did I do?
我做了什么？
You're under arrest for distribution of meth.
你因为私藏毒品被捕
Meth? Dwight's never touched that shit, bro!
毒品？我从不碰那玩意
Dwight has now.
现在碰了
Yo, that ain't mine! No!
那不是我的！
You know that's never gonna stick, right?
你知道这从来站不住脚的 对吧？
Yeah, it's not supposed to.
是啊
Live it up! Live it up!
加油！
Yeah, Corona.
科罗娜啤酒
That's too bad about Dwight.
德怀特太不幸了
Having the Feds raid your house the same night you make the team.
你进入他们组织那晚联邦调查局 搜查了他的房子
So unfortunate.
真不幸
I wish I could say I was surprised to see you here.
我想说我真没想到在这遇见你
What's to stop someone from telling them you're a cop?
怎样才能让我不告诉他们你是警察
Probably the same thing that's keeping me from telling them why you're really here.
和我不告诉他们你来这的真正目的 是一回事吧
- What up, fellows? - Hey, how you doing?
- 你们好吗 伙计们 - 你好
- Great. You having a good time? - Yeah, a great time.
- 玩得开心吗？ - 很开心
Come on, let's have a better time.
跟我来 找点乐子
How's your car? It took a nasty bump.
你的车怎么样了？撞得不轻啊
lt'll be ready.
会好的
I also heard you just got out of County.
我听说你刚从牢里出来
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
嗯
You know a guy named Jim Garcia?
听说过吉姆·加西亚吗？
Nah. Big place. Lots of names, lots of faces.
没有 地方大 很多名字 很多面孔
And you, you're wanted by a lot of people, homes.
你 很多人要抓你
Yeah, that kind of heat can't be good for business.
那可对生意不好
Yeah, well, that depends on how you look at things.
那要看你怎么看这件事
I go down, I do time.
我被抓 我坐牢
I do real time.
真的坐牢
I don't know about your other drivers, but when I see flashing lights in my mirror,
我不知道别人怎么样 只要我看到后面警车在追
I don't stop.
我可不会停
Do you know each other?
你们两个认识吗？
He used to date my sister.
他曾泡我妹妹
I see.
明白了
- You're a lucky man. - How's that?
- 你很走运 - 怎讲？
You're still breathing.
你还活着
To the ladies we've loved and the ladies we've lost.
为我们爱过和失去过的女人们干杯
So, what's Braga about?
布拉加怎么样？
You know, he's just one of us.
他和我们一样
Came up from the streets. Down for el barrio.
发迹于街头 最后入狱
Now he's a shot caller.
现在他是发号施令的人
The boss of bosses.
老大中的老大
See all these cats in here?
瞧见这些人了吗？
Any one of them would die for Braga.
他们都愿意为布拉加去死
lncluding you?
包括你？
Especially me.
特别是我
Enjoy the party, fellows. Club's yours.
好好玩 伙计们 这是你们的地盘
Whatever you want, booze, broads, it's all good.
不管你们要什么 美酒 佳人 都行
Braga's mine.
布拉加是我的
I'm taking the whole house down.
我要把他们一网打尽
Good luck.
好运
Something interests you about this car?
对这辆车很感兴趣？
Just admiring the body work.
欣赏车身设计
Are you one of those boys who prefers cars to women?
你是那种喜欢车胜过女人的人吗？
I'm one of those boys that appreciates a fine body, regardless of the make.
我是那种喜欢完美身形的人 不管是车还是女人
Your car?
你的车？
It's Fenix's car.
菲尼克斯的车
You'll meet him at the rendezvous. He'll be leading you.
你会在接头地点见到他 他给你们领路
So now
现在…
that I know your taste in cars,
我知道了你对车的品味
tell me, what about your women?
告诉我 你的女人什么样子？
It all starts with the eyes.
一切都是从眼睛开始的
She's got to have those kind of eyes that can look right through the bullshit
她那双眼睛能穿过浮夸的外表
to the good in someone.
看到一个人的本质
20% angel, 80% devil.
二分天使 八分魔鬼
Down to earth.
来到人间
Ain't afraid to get a little engine grease under her fingernails.
一点都不怕指甲上沾上机油
That doesn't sound anything like me.
听起来一点都不像我
It ain't.
是的
- Hi. - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- I got a gift for you. - All right.
- 送你个礼物 - 好啊
A dirty shot glass, just what I always wanted.
脏酒杯 我一直想要的
I got these from the club last night.
我昨晚从俱乐部弄来的
There's two sets of prints here. Run them both.
他们两个的指纹都在上面
I know one of these is Campos'. I think the other might be Braga's.
我知道一个是坎波斯的 另一个很可能是布拉加的
And you're gonna have to go beyond lnterpol.
你要联系国际刑警组织
So, that means I have to contact individual agencies,
那意味着我要联系每一位探员
and that could take weeks. Okay.
这要好几周时间 好吧
Yeah.
喂
That's your third traffic violation in less than three blocks.
不到3个街区你就3次违章了
Slow it down, O'Conner.
慢点 奥康纳
Sure thing, Dad.
没问题 老爹
He stopped.
他停下了
We lost him.
我们跟丢了
He killed the tracker. We don't know that.
他关掉了跟踪器 我们还不知道
I'm telling you, he killed the tracker. We don't know that yet!
我告诉你 他关掉了跟踪器 我们还不知道！
Get the bird overhead.
直升机出动
Right now, I'm moving north, 33', 56'...
正向北飞行 33度56分
All clear.
安全
Base, fIag nine, I'm at AngeIs 5.
呼叫总部
I don't have a taIIy on the target. Repeat, I don't have a taIIy on the target.
没发现目标 重复 没发现目标
They're gone, there's no one down there.
他们走了 那下面没人
Damn it!
见鬼！
This ain't right, bro. Nobody said nothing about being locked in no truck.
这不对 老兄 没人说过被锁在卡车里
Tell me about it.
怎么回事
Hey. Hey!
嘿 嘿！
Yo! Where do you think they're taking us?
你认为他们带我们去哪？
Don't matter.
无所谓
We're all just along for the ride now.
我们现在只是凑热闹的
Welcome to Mexico, boys.
欢迎来到墨西哥 小伙子们
There are helicopters and surveillance cameras
直升机和监视摄像头
that scan for heat signatures at the border.
扫描边界的热信号
But there are blind spots that I can guide you through via satellite.
但是存在盲点 通过卫星我可以引导你们穿过去
There can be no margin of error, so you must follow my every direction.
绝对不能犯错 因此你们必须遵守指示
Any questions?
有问题吗？
I thought Fenix was gonna be here.
我认为菲尼克斯会在那
He'll meet you out there.
他在外面等你们
All right, everybody, sync up.
好啦 大家同步
Good luck, gentlemen.
好运 先生们
SateIIite Iinkup engaged.
卫星已连接
Keep proceeding northbound at current speed.
以当前速度前往北部边界
Stay cIose to Fenix.
跟紧菲尼克斯
He'II Iead you across.
他将带你们穿过边境
I got a heat signature northbound along Legardo Ravine.
隆加多峡谷北侧发现热信号
Thermal imaging window on the Mexico side's gonna be down for about 45 seconds.
墨西哥一侧的热信号窗口要关闭45秒
Get the camera on it.
使用摄像头
Manual override. Rerouting camera to designated coordinates.
人工操作 设定摄像头到指定坐标
Hurry it up. You guys have been tagged.
快点 你们被盯上了
Shit.
糟糕
Toretto, get back in formation.
特伦托 获取背后情况
Reimaging commencing.
重新成像开始
I don't see anything.
什么都没发现
They're gone.
他们跑掉了
Get the helicopters to cover it.
派直升机去监视
Base, we're 40 seconds out from Legardo Ravine.
总部 我们离开隆加多峡谷40秒
They're sending a heIicopter.
他们派了直升机
You have 30 seconds.
你们有30秒时间
North 32' 33', west 116' 49'.
北纬32度33分 西经116度49分
The window is cIosing fast.
窗口很快就要关闭
You need to get out of there before they send ground support.
你们要在他们派出地面支援之前离开那
Fifteen seconds.
15秒
Base, target is at two miIes.
总部 距离目标2英里
You're running out of time.
你们没时间了
You need to get out now!
你们快离开那！
Base, we're at north 32' 33', west 116' 49'.
总部 我们在北纬32度33分 西经116度49分
We have no visuaI contact. RoII ground units for confirmation.
没发现目标 出动地面部队以确认
Sloppy!
慢！
Very sloppy!
太慢了！
What are you doing, man?
你在做什么？
Come on.
快点
Get out.
出来
Come on, man.
快点
Come on, today, man. Come on, let's go.
快点 我们走
Hey, don't touch me. Hey, don't touch me, man!
嘿 别碰我！嘿 别碰我！
Hey, I said don't touch me, man!
我说别碰我！
Hey, look, dawg, don't put your hands on me.
把手从我身上拿开
Hey, Malik, chill, bro.
马利克
Yo, man, what's up with your boy?
你们怎么回事？
Hey, boss man!
嘿 老大！
What did you say?
你说什么？
I said only pussies run nitrometh.
我说只有脓包用硝基甲烷
You looked under my hood?
你检查过我的车？
I'm talking to you.
在和你说话呢
Got something on your mind?
你在想什么？
'70 Plymouth.
70款普利茅斯
Her name was Letty.
她叫莱蒂
Where's my money?
我的钱呢？
And somebody wrecked her car.
有人撞毁了她的车
I wrecked her car.
我撞的
You remember her face?
你还记得那张脸吗？
Huh?
嗯？
'Cause I don't.
我可忘了
Last time I saw it, it was burning.
上次我见到它 在燃烧
Now what?
现在又怎样？
I'm going to enjoy what happens next.
我会享受接下来这一刻
Dom, get in!
多姆 上车！
Get in! Come on!
快上车！
Come on! Get in the fucking car! Let's go! Hurry up!
快点！快上车！
What have you got, Trinh?
发现了什么？
We're contacting agencies in multiple countries.
我们在联系各国的特工
Unfortunately, most of them have to manually scan their prints for us to upload.
很不幸 他们大多数都要手动 扫描指纹上传
O'Conner's on line five.
奥康纳在5号线
And, sir, you should see this.
长官 您看看这个
Thank you.
谢谢
Talk to me, O'Conner.
讲话 奥康纳
- Where the hell have you been? - I got the shipment.
- 你到底去哪了？ - 我拿到货了
"I got the shipment", or  "we got the shipment"?
“我拿到货” 还是“我们拿到货”？
What are you taIking about?
你在说什么？
Traffic cams in the area picked up pictures of you and Toretto together.
交通监视器录到你和特伦托在一起的画面
Listen to me, O'Conner. Bring in the shipment and bring in Toretto.
听者 奥康纳 把货带来 把特伦托带来
But I thought the point was to get Braga. We got an opportunity here.
但我认为目标是布拉加 我们现在有机会
Brian, the clock stopped ticking.
布莱恩 没时间了
Bring them in. Are we cIear?
把他们带来 明白吗？
O'Conner?
奥康纳？
So this is what $60 million looks like.
六千万就是这样子
Yeah, we got to get you to a doctor.
嗯 你得去找医生看看
We got to find a place to hide this.
我们要找个地方把它藏起来
I got a spot.
我有个地方
502, wet reckless. I need a 48-hour hold.
502号 酒后驾车 需要48小时扣押
Out back. Any spot you can find.
找个地方吧
You sure about this?
这没问题吗？
Yeah. The last place they'll check, their own impound yard. Trust me.
是的 他们最不会搜查的地方 就是自己的押车场 相信我吧
You know, I've been thinking,
我在想…
when you blew up your car back there, you blew up mine, too.
你炸毁你的车的时候 把我的也炸了
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
So now you owe me a 10-second car.
你欠我一辆跑车
- Is that right? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是的
Now we're even.
现在扯平了
Is this your way of keeping me away from him?
你就这样让我离他远点？
- You're the only one I could call. - He's my brother, of course.
- 你是我唯一能求助的人 - 他是我哥哥 当然
The bullet's not in there.
子弹不在里面
I'm gonna clean it and stitch it up. It's going to hurt.
我要清洗干净然后缝上 会有点疼
I bet you're going to enjoy this.
我打赌你很享受这个
A little.
有点
- Want some of this? - Yeah.
- 要这个吗？ - 嗯
It's spicy.
辣的
I like it hot.
我很喜欢
Dom, what are you doing?
多姆 你怎么了？
You reached first, you have to say grace.
你太着急了 要先祈祷的
Thank you, Lord, for blessing this table.
感谢上帝
With food, family and friendship.
赐给我们食物 家庭和友情
You asked me why I let Dom go.
你问我为什么放走多姆
I think it's because at that moment,
我想是因为那个时刻
I respected him more than I did myself.
我尊重他胜过我自己
Yeah.
嗯
One thing I learned from Dom is that nothing really matters unless you have a code.
我从多姆身上学到的是 什么都不重要 除非你有准则
And what's your code, Brian?
你的准则是什么 布莱恩？
I'm working on it.
正在找呢
Shit. Hey, Dom.
不好 嘿 多姆
- When were you gonna tell me? - Dom, what are you doing?
- 你打算什么时候告诉我？ - 多姆 你在做什么？
When were you gonna tell me you were running Letty?
你打算什么时候告诉我 是你在背后指使莱蒂？
- Let me explain... - When were you gonna...
- 让我解释… - 你打算什么时候…
Dom, stop!
多姆 住手！
- You don't understand. - I don't understand?
- 你不明白 - 我不明白？
Stop!
住手！
She did it for...
她是为了…
Dom, stop!
多姆 住手！
Dom, stop it! Please stop!
住手！拜托！
She did it for you, Dom! She did it for you!
她是为你 多姆！为你！
Letty came to me to clear your name in exchange for bringing down Braga.
莱蒂来找我要以为布拉加运货 来交换把你的名字从名单上除去
She just wanted you to come home!
她是为了让你回家！
I'm sorry, Dom!
对不起 多姆！
I'm sorry!
对不起！
You better have one hell of an explanation. You disobeyed a direct order.
你最好有个解释 你直接违抗命令
- Where's the shipment? - It's safe.
- 货在哪？ - 很安全
It's safe.
安全
Look, we could use the shipment to parade in front of the media,
听者 我们可以拿这批货在媒体宣传
get a few hundred pounds of heroin off the street,
说是从街头查获了几百磅海洛因
but Braga's just gonna send another shipment next week and the week after that.
但是布拉加以后还会运更多的货进来
Let's use the shipment to lure Braga out
我们用这批货把布拉加引出来
and lop the head off a multi-billion dollar cartel.
把他们的头抓住
And how do you suggest we do that?
我们怎样做？
A hand-to-hand exchange with Braga.
和布拉加面对面交易
He'll never show.
他从不出现
He can't afford not to.
他不得不露面
You got a plan?
你有计划吗？
There's a price.
我们谈个交易
We bag Braga, you let Toretto walk.
我们抓住布拉加 你放了特伦托
- Yes? - It's Dom.
- 喂 - 我是多姆
I was just thinking about you.
我正想你呢
You know, when I gave you my number, I was hoping you'd call.
我给你我的号码的时候 希望你能打过来
But not under these circumstances.
但不是这种情况下
What circumstances? Me being alive?
什么情况下？我活着？
Don't take it personaIIy.
别对个人
It's just business.
这是公事
I got some business of my own.
我自己有点公事
Get Campos.
让坎波斯接电话
It's them.
是他们
Uh-huh.
嗯
Was that how Braga inspires loyalty? Killing his drivers?
布拉加就这样表现诚意？ 卸磨杀驴？
One can always find more drivers.
总能找到更多的车手
It's just good business.
这是个好生意
I want to trade.
我要做笔交易
Braga doesn't negotiate.
布拉加从不谈判
Fine.
好吧
You explain to him how all of a sudden $60 million worth of product disappears.
你向他解释六千万的货怎么就不见了
I know that can't be good for business.
我知道这对生意可不好
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Six million cash, delivered by Braga himself.
六百万现金 布拉加亲自送过来
I don't Iike being shot at.
我可不想当靶子
I ain't gonna put my neck out again unless he's got something to lose, too.
我可不想冒生命危险 除非他也冒险前来
He'll never go for it.
他不会来的
Either I deal with Braga, or you do.
或者我和布拉加打交道 或者你去
When and where?
时间和地点？
Sir, players are onsite. Holding positions at the perimeter.
队员已经就位 周围待命
All right. Listen up. Everybody stay frosty.
听者 所有人待命
We don't move a muscIe untiI O'Conner gives the signaI.
接到奥康纳信号前不得行动
When he gets the money, you know what to do.
他拿到钱的时候 我们知道该怎么办
Well, the good news is, when we get this guy,
好消息是 我们抓住这家伙时
you walk out of here a free man.
你就自由了
Is that what they told you?
他们这样和你说的？
Yeah, that's the deal.
是的 这是协议
You still put milk and cookies out for Santa Claus?
你还信圣诞老人这回事？
Yeah.
是啊
Here.
来了
ln case things go shitty.
以防万一
Just like old times?
像以前一样？
Yeah.
嗯
You dropped something.
你掉东西了
- That's what you wanted, - right? Dom...
- 这就是你想要的？ - 多姆…
He's harmless. Don't worry about him.
他没恶意 别担心
And he's really sorry about Letty.
他真的为莱蒂遗憾
Where's our stuff?
我们的货呢？
You mean the stuff that used to be in here, right?
曾经在这里面的货吗？
Well, you'll see it when we see Braga. That was the deal.
我们见到布拉加 你就能见到货 这是协议
No worries.
别担心
Braga keeps his word.
布拉加守信的
$2 million.
二百万
You get the rest when I get my property.
我拿到我的东西后给你们剩下的钱
- Stasiak. - We got a match.
- 斯特萨克 - 我们找到匹配了
The fingerprint's Braga's 100%.
指纹100%是布拉加的
Just waiting on faciaI confirmation via fax.
正等待传真面部确认
I got a question for you.
我有个问题
You wearing pink when you were clawing your way out of el barrio?
你越狱时候穿的是粉的？
Order all agents to move in.
所有特警准备行动
We got confirmation. Primary suspect wearing gray suit.
我们得到确认 头号疑犯身着灰色西装
Let's move.
行动
Sir, O'Conner hasn't given us the signal yet.
长官 奥康纳还没给出信号
What part of that didn't you understand? We just got confirmation. Do it!
你哪部分不明白？ 我们刚得到确认 快行动！
Secure primary suspect in gray suit. Repeat!
头号疑犯身着灰色西装 重复！
Secure primary suspect in gray suit.
头号疑犯身着灰色西装
You're thinking what I'm thinking, right?
你在想我在想什么 对吧？
He ain't Braga.
他不是布拉加
Oh, shit.
糟糕
Drop your weapons! FBl!
放下武器！联邦调查局的！
Get down!
趴下！
Get out of here!
离开这！
Get out of here, Dom!
离开这 多姆！
Run him down.
撞死他
Go!
快走！
Campos is Braga!
坎波斯就是布拉加！
Come on.
快走
Approaching primary target.
接近头号目标中
Primary suspect is secure.
疑犯安全
He was under your nose the whoIe time.
全程他都在你们鼻子底下
Now Braga's escaped.
现在布拉加跑了
Toretto's heading south, probably long across the border by now.
特伦托向南边跑了 很可能越过了边界
Do you have any idea the kind of trouble you're in, O'Conner?
你知道你惹了什么麻烦吗 奥康纳先生？
I was doing my job.
我在做我的工作
He ain't the first bad guy you helped escape the law's grasp.
他不是第一个你协助逃脱法律制裁的人
As of now, you're being taken off active duty,
你被停职了
until this house can mount a formal inquiry.
直到举行正式听证会
What about Braga?
布拉加呢？
That's no longer your concern.
你不用再操心了
We now know where Braga is, right?
我们知道了布拉加在哪
Customs tracked him via satellite to his home base in Tecali, Mexico.
海关通过卫星追踪他到他的老巢 墨西哥的台卡利
Mexico is out of our jurisdiction.
我们在墨西哥没有执法权
The fact is
事实是
the brass will be so busy holding press conferences over the seizure,
官员们忙着召开新闻发布会解释这次抓捕
we'll skate under the radar.
我们在背后行动
I thought we signed on to do the right thing.
我认为我们的工作是做正确的事情
Everyone's looking for you.
大家都在找你
I'm right here.
我就在这
It's nice to see you've gone with the times
很高兴看到你走出往事
and switched to electronic fuel injection. Looks good.
换成了电子燃料注入 看上去不错
Buster became a gearhead.
菜鸟成专家了
I'm going with you.
我和你去
I don't plan on bringing anyone back.
我没打算带任何人回来
I know.
我知道
Hit that throttle.
按下阀门
Hey.
嘿
How do you say goodbye to your only brother?
你怎样和你唯一的哥哥道别？
You don't.
你不需要
I thought you weren't gonna show up.
我以为你不会出现的
You saved my life.
你救了我的命
I'm willing to return the favor.
我想还你个情
This will help get you to Braga.
这会帮你找到布拉加
Dom.
多姆
Going in there is suicide.
去那是自杀
I have no choice.
我别无选择
You must have loved her very much.
你一定很爱她
So this is where my jurisdiction ends.
我的权力到这就结束了
And this is where mine begins.
我的才刚开始
- welcome to the house of the lord, Sr.Braga. - Don't worry father, everthing's go.
- 欢迎来到布拉加阁下的房子 - 别担心 神父 一切都会好起来的
To help us get to heaven.
帮我们去天堂
Please receive this blessing.
请接收这份祝福
You ain't forgiven.
你不会被宽恕的
You boys want to arrest me?
你们要逮捕我？
...in here.
在这里？
No, we're beyond that.
不 远不止
You can't buy your way out of this one.
这次你跑不了了
You and me...
你和我…
You and me, we're not so different.
你和我没什么不同
You're no hero.
你不是英雄
You're right.
说得没错
And that's why you're going back across the border.
所以你逃回了边界
But Fenix is mine.
菲尼克斯是我的
You got it.
没问题
Shit!
不好！
You'll make it a couple of miles out, if you're lucky.
如果你能跑出两英里 算你走运
You know where you're going?
你知道你要去哪吗？
You want to borrow my GPS?
想借我的GPS？
Where are your boys at?
你的人呢？
Are they going to show up or what?
还出不出现？
Careful what you ask for.
你得小心点
Just stop. Just stop the car.
停车 停车吧
Don't shoot the boss, idiots.
别打着老板 笨蛋
Right behind you.
就在你后面
Dom, head to the tunnel. Let's use the tunnel.
多姆 前往隧道 我们利用隧道
Get out of here, Brian.
离开这 布莱恩
You sure you know where the tunnels are? You sure?
你确定知道隧道在哪？确定吗？
Yeah. I'd hold on.
是的 我会抓紧点
This might hurt.
这可能会疼
You're in my world now, baby!
现在到我的地盘了 宝贝
That's it, baby! End of the road.
就这样 宝贝！前面没路了
Now what?
现在想怎样？
Game over.
玩完了
No, no, no.
不
Come on!
快点！
Hey!
嘿！
Get me out of here!
那我弄出来！
Pussy.
脓包
Let me see that.
我看看
Yeah. Just keep pressure there.
压住
You'll be all right.
你会没事的
You gotta get out of here.
你得离开这
I ain't running anymore.
我不再逃跑了
I gotta ask you something.
我问你件事
Yeah?
嗯？
You know I would have won that race if you didn't cheat, right?
你知道如果你不作弊 那次赛车我就赢了 对吧
You hit your head hard.
你头撞得不轻吧
Don't make me laugh.
别让我笑了
All rise.
全体起立
Please be seated.
请坐
Please rise, Mr. Toretto.
请起立 特伦托先生
I've listened to the testimony
我听了证词
and taken into special consideration
特别考虑了
Agent O'Conner's appeal of clemency on behalf of Mr. Toretto.
奥康纳探员为特伦托先生的请愿
That his actions directly resulted in the apprehension
他的行为直接导致大毒枭
of known drug trafficker Arturo Braga.
阿图罗·布拉加的被捕
However,
但是
this judiciary finds that
司法部认为
one right does not make up for a lifetime worth of wrongs.
一件正确的事不能弥补一生犯下的错
And as such,
因此
I find that I am forced to level the maximum sentence under California law.
我不得不按加州法律判最终刑期
Dominic Toretto,
多米尼克·特伦托
you are hereby sentenced to serve 25 years to life
你被判在隆波克监狱
at the Lompoc maximum security prison system
最高安全等级监禁25年
without the possibiIity of earIy paroIe.
不得假释
This court is adjourned.
休庭